

# Balasundar S

**Backend Developer** 

balasundar2796@gmail.com

9486030662

Chennai, Tamilnadu, India - 600017

sbalasundar.github.io/

linkedin.com/in/balasundars in

github.com/SBalaSundar

stackoverflow.com/users/12972867/balasundar

Grounded and solution-oriented developer with sound knowledge and experience in Python, Django, Flask and wide variety of professional experiences. Driven and self motivated, and therefore effective at completing tasks with minimal supervision. Also a confident leader with the experience of organizing events, team management and co-ordination.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Associate Software Engineer**

Ventuno Technologies 🗷

01/2020 - Present

Chennai, Tamilnadu, India

Tasks and Achievements:

- Technologies: Django, REST API, Python, Unit Test, Test Driven Development.
- Developed REST APIs for User management, Partner management, Monetization and Analytics in Django for Ventuno Online OTT Platform in a effective and innovative way.

# **Back-End Developer**

Fame Technologies 🗷

08/2019 - 12/2019

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Tasks and Achievements:
- Technologies: Flask, Django, REST API, Python, PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL.
- Developed REST APIs for the company's web application using Flask.
- Implemented company's first career portal using Django.
- Developed a program to generate ID cards of the employees automatically in Python (using Image package). It helped the designers to save a lot of time.

# **Technician**

# Mepco Schlenk Engineering College 🗷

07/2014 - 03/2016

Sivakasi, Tamilnadu, India

- Tasks and Achievements:
- Performing or ensuring proper installation of cables, operating systems(Linux and Microsoft Windows), or appropriate software.
- Install and perform minor repairs to hardware, software, or peripheral equipment.
- Monitor and troubleshooting computer network inside the department.
- Assisting the teaching faculties during the lab sessions.

# **SKILLS**

#### Frameworks:

Django, Flask

#### Languages:

Python, C, Java, PHP, VB.NET, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery

#### Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle 10g/11g, MS Access, MS SQL Server

#### Methodologies:

REST APIs, Test Driven Development, Unit Test

#### Computer Networks:

Design, implementation & troubleshooting of small networks. Configuration of Servers and Routers

#### Operating Systems:

Microsoft Windows 7/8/10, Linux (Ubuntu, Linux mint, Kali Linux), Android.

#### Hardware and Software:

Assembly, Maintenance, Troubleshooting

PyCharm, Eclipse, NetBeans, MS Visual Studio, Git, Selenium

# SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork

**Flexibility** 

Self-management

Leadership

### INTERESTS

Robotics

Swimming

📇 Gardening

Traveling

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

Web Application For Agricultural Development (08/2013 - 04/2014)

A Website to help the farmers, improve the Productivity and avoid price drop.

# **EDUCATION**

B.E Computer Science and Engineering

Mepco Schlenk Engineering College

06/2016 – 04/2019

6.9 GPA

**Diploma in Computer Engineering**Arasan Ganesan Polytechnic College

06/2011 - 04/2014

77 %

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Active Volunteer

National Service Scheme

07/2016 - 07/2018

Tasks/Achievements

- Actively volunteered on more than fifteen events. As a team we planted more than thousand trees inside of our college campus.
- Planted thousand trees inside of our college campus as a team.
- Co convener

Institution of Engineers(India)

06/2016 - 04/2019

Tasks/Achievements

 Organized six events in three technical symposiums from 2016 to 2019, attended by more than a hundred participants each.

# **LANGUAGES**

Tamil

English

Native

Full Professional Proficiency

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

Online Computer Service Management System (08/2018 – 12/2018)

 Goal of this project is to access the computer services at the doorstep. The customers describes about the problem by using this Application. Based on the problems, It assigns jobs to the service engineers who are all expert in their fields.

Tuberculosis Detection Using Chest X-Rays (12/2018 – 04/2019) ☑

 Detection of Tuberculosis from chest X-Ray images at an earlier stage as soon as possible with higher accuracy by extracting features from the X-Ray images and Constructing CNN.

# **CERTIFICATES**

Diploma in Yoga for Youth Empowerment.

Vethathri Maharishi Institute for Spiritual and Institutional Education, 2017

Joy of Computing Using Python

NPTEL, Indian Institute of Technology Madras, 2018

Cambridge English Entry Level Certificate in ESOL International(Entry 3) (Business)

Cambridge Assessment English, 2018